Do you realize we're getting married in four weeks?
你知道再四个星期 我们就要结婚了吗？
Four weeks, baby. Four weeks!
四个星期，宝贝，四个星期！
You realize you get louder each week?
你知道每星期你都更大声吗？
There's still so much to do! Have you written your vows?
还有这么多事要做！ 你写好你的婚誓了吗？
I figured I'd just buy those. "Pat, I'd like to buy a vow."
我想我会去买 “派得，我要买婚誓”
You know I've no sense of humor when it comes to this.
你知道讲到婚礼的事 我是没有幽默感的
-Right. Have you written yours yet? -No, but I know what I'm gonna say.
-是，你写了你的吗？ -不，我知道我要说什么
Do you happen to know what I'm gonna say?
你会不会刚好知道 我要讲什么？
Let's do it now. It won't be hard.
现在来做，不会那么难的
Say what's in your heart.
说你心里想的
Look at her go. She must love me more than I love her!
看她写得多快，她一定爱我 比我爱她多！
What's wrong with me? Oh, don't open that door.
我有什么问题？ 不要打开那扇门
The One with the Vows
本集播出：婚誓
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
"Monica, there are no words.."
“摩妮卡，没有字…”
There are no words! This shouldn't be this hard!
没有字！不应该这么难的！
You've done this before. What did you say in your vows?
你做过这事 你的婚誓里说什么？
With Carol I promised never to love another woman until I die.
对卡萝，我答应直到我死 不再爱另一个女人
She made no such promise.
她没有这样答应我
I'm pathetic. Monica knows what to say, you should have seen her.
我真悲哀，摩妮卡知道要讲什么 看她下笔如飞的样子
What's the emergency?
什么紧急大事？
You have to help me write my vows. All I have is this.
帮我忙，我需要写我的婚誓 可是我只有这些
I like the pretty drawing of you in the wedding dress.
我喜欢你穿婚纱的图划
-Thank you. -Except your breasts look small.
除了你的胸部看来有点小
Those are my eyes!
那些是我的眼睛！
-Those are my breasts. -Oh, yeah.
-那是我的胸部 -是，好吧
Why don't you start with something simple?
何不从简单的开始，像是：
"Monica, from the moment I met you I knew I loved you."
“摩妮卡，第一次见到你 我就知道我爱你”
I can't do that.
我不确定我能这么说
Everyone, this is Chandler.
各位，这是钱德
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister.
我是罗斯的小妹
Okay.
是
Okay, okay. Maybe you could start with:
好，也许这样起头：
"Chandler, even though we were friends...
钱德，即使在我们还是朋友时…
there was a part of me that knew I wanted more."
一部份的我一直知道我要更多
All right, there's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on Earth.
好吧，有一场核子浩劫 我是地球上最后一个男人
Would you go out with me?
你会和我约会吗？
Are we allowed to lie in the vows?
婚誓里可以说谎吗？
Okay, don't talk about those feelings. Just say something about...
也许那时你不谈你的感情
all the things he's taught you, like..
说些他教会你的事，像是…
Or all the things you taught him.
或是你教会他的事
Everybody knows the erogenous zones. One, two, three...
大家都知道基本的性感带 有1，2，3…
four, five, six and seven.
4，5… 6和7
There are seven?
有7个？
-That's one? -Kind of an important one.
-那算是一个吗？ -蛮重要的
I was looking at it upside down.
我是倒着看的
You know, sometimes that helps.
有时候这样也有帮助的
Okay, start out with a little one...
好，现在，由1开始…
a two, a one-two-three...
一个2，一个123…
a three, a five...
一个3，一个5…
a four, a three-two...
一个4，一个32…
two, a two-four-six.
2，一个246
Two-four-six, four, two...
246，4，2…
two, four-seven...
2，47…
five-seven, six-seven...
57，67…
seven, seven...
7，7…
seven, seven, seven...
7，7，7，7，7…
seven!
7！
How about something like:
我知道了！这样如何：
"Monica, when I look back over our time together..."
“摩妮卡，回顾我们在一起的时间…”
-Yeah? -I can't do all of it.
-然后？ -不能全部都要我做
Look back over your time together.
回顾你们在一起的时间
Oh, look, twins!
看，双胞胎！
No fair! I don't even have one, how come they get two?
不公平！我连一个都没有 为什么他们有两个？
-You'll get one. -Yeah, when?
-你会有一个的 -是啊，什么时候？
When we're 40, if neither of us are married...
这样吧 当我们40的时候，如果我们 都没结婚，
-what do you say we have one? -Why wouldn't I be married?
-我们俩来生一个如何？ -我为什么会40岁还没结婚？
I just meant hypothetically.
不，不，我是说假设这样
Hypothetically, why won't I be married?
假设这样 我为什么会40岁还没结婚？
No, no.
不，不
What is it? Is there something unmarriable about me?
怎么着？真的，我是有什么 基本上不能结婚的地方吗？
Well?
怎么样？
Dear God, this parachute is a knapsack!
我的老天 这个降落伞是一个背包！
I'm getting married today!
今天我要结婚了！
Think he knew I was here?
他知道我在这儿吗？
Nice try.
算你尽力
Wait, wait, wait.
等一下，等一下，等一下
Look, Monica..
摩妮卡…
-This is not gonna work. -I bet this'll work.
-没有用的 -我保证这有用
You are so great! I love you.
你真棒！我爱你
What?
什么？
I said you're so great, and then I stopped talking.
没事！我说，你真棒 然后就没说话了
-You said you love me! -No, I didn't.
-你说你爱我！我不能相信 -不，我没有
-Yes, you did. -No, I didn't!
-有，你有 -没有，我没有！
-You love me! -No, I don't!
-你爱我！ -不，我不！
Stop it! Stop it!
停！停！
You know, I was thinking, what if I unpack here?
我在想，如果我在这里打开东西呢？
Then all your stuff would be here.
你的东西都会在这里
Well...
那…
What if it was here?
如果我的东西都在这里的话？
Then you'd be going back and forth all the time.
你会一直来来往往的
Doesn't make any sense.
没什么道理
Okay.
好
What if we live together, and you understand what I'm saying?
如果我们住在一起 你了解我在说什么？
We wanted to surprise you.
你希望这是一个惊喜
Oh, my God!
我的天！
Chandler...
钱德…
in all my life...
我这一生…
I never thought I'd be so lucky...
从没想过我会这么幸运…
as to fall in love with my best..
能爱上我最好的…
My best.. There's a reason why girls don't do this!
我最好的… 女生不这么做是有原因的！
Okay, okay, okay! I'll do it.
好，好，我来
I thought..
我想…
I can do this.
我做得到
I thought...
我以为…
that it mattered what I said or where I said it.
我说什么和在哪里说很重要
Then I realized the only thing that matters is that you..
但我发现唯一重要的是你…
You make me happier than I ever thought I could be.
你使我比我能想像的更快乐
And if you let me...
如果你愿意…
I'll spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
我要用这一生 来让你有同样感觉
Monica?
摩妮卡？
Will you marry me?
嫁给我好吗？
Yes.
好
Can we come in? We're dying out here!
我们可以进来了吗？ 我们要急死了！
Come in! Come in!
进来！进来！
-We're engaged! -Yes!
-我们订婚了！ -好！
-Hi. -What have you guys been up to?
-嗨 -你们在干嘛？
Helping Chandler write his vows. He kicked us out.
帮钱德写他的婚誓 但被他踢出来了…
Joey kept making inappropriate suggestions.
因为乔伊一直做不恰当的建议
How is "Monica, I love your sweet ass" inappropriate?
“摩妮卡，我爱你的美臀” 有什么不恰当？
How's Monica doing?
摩妮卡写得怎么样？
Lucky she's got a sweet ass. She's not so good at writing.
这样说吧，幸好她有一个美臀 因为她不太会写
In four weeks they're gonna be married!
真不能相信再四个星期 他们就要结婚了！
Let's just hope it works.
希望他们的婚姻成功
Nine out of 10 marriages end in divorce.
10个里面有9个以离婚收场
That's not true.
菲比，没有的事
You're right. How's the missis?
是啊，你说的对，你太太们好吗？
I can't believe...
真不能相信...
-they're together 3 years. -That long?
-...他们在一起3年了 -那么久了？
It seems like less because they hid it from us.
感觉没那么久 因为他们瞒了我们很久
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
是我，进来了
I've had a very long, hard day.
我今天辛苦了一整天
-I'm getting some chicken. Want some? -No. Bye, then.
-我要去买炸鸡，你要不要？ -不，谢了，不要炸鸡，再见
He wouldn't leave. He kept asking if I wanted chicken.
你还好吧？抱歉，他不肯离开 一直问要不要炸鸡
Chicken?
炸鸡？
I could eat some chicken.
我可以来点炸鸡
Hey, Joe!
乔伊！
Can I get a three-piece, coleslaw, beans and a Coke?
我想要三块鸡，沙拉 豆子，还有可乐
Diet Coke.
健怡可乐
-Why didn't they tell us? -I know, we were cool about it.
-我不知道他们为什么不告诉我们 -好像我们不会认同似的
You? And you?
你？和你？
You cannot tell. No one knows.
你不能说，没有人知道
How? When?
怎么？何时？
-It happened in London. -In London?!
-在伦敦发生的 -在伦敦？！
We didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
我们没告诉任何人 不希望把它变成大事
But it is a big deal!
可是这是大事！
-I have to tell someone. -No, no!
-我一定要告诉人 -不，不要！
-You can't. -Please!
-你不能 -拜托！
We don't want to deal with telling them. Just promise you won't tell.
我们不想面对告诉大家之后的事 答应我你不会说
All right!
好！
I can't wait to be with you. I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry.
等不及要和你在一起了，我告诉瑞秋我要洗几个小时的衣服
Laundry? Is that my new nickname?
洗衣服？是我的新昵称吗？
You know your nickname, Mr. Big..
你知道你的昵称是什么，大…
Oh, look, there's Monica and Chandler. Hey! Hey, you guys! Hey!
看，是摩妮卡和钱德 嘿！嘿，你们两个！嘿！
Chandler and Monica!
钱德和摩妮卡！ 钱德和摩妮卡！
Oh, my God!
我的天！
-Chandler and Monica! -Oh, my God!
-钱德和摩妮卡！ -我的天！
-Oh, my eyes! My eyes! -Phoebe! Phoebe!
-我的眼睛！我的眼睛！ -菲比！菲比！
-It's okay! It's okay! -No! They're doing it!
-没事的！没事的！ -不！他们在亲热！
I know! I know!
我知道！我知道！
-You know? -Yes!
-你知道？ -对，我知道！
And Joey, but Ross doesn't, so stop screaming!
乔伊知道，但罗斯不知道 你得停止尖叫！
-Hey, what's going on? -Oh, hi!
-怎么样啊？ -嗨！
What? What?
什么？什么？
We're excited that you might get this place!
老天！我们好兴奋 你可能会搬来这儿！
-Actually, it looks really good. -It looks pretty good!
-事实上，看起来不错 -看来很不错！
Get in here! Come on!
过来这里！来！
So they don't know that Rachel knows?
他们知道你知道 但他们不知道瑞秋知道？
Yes, but it doesn't matter who knows what.
对，但你知道吗？ 谁知道什么并不重要
Enough of us know. We can just tell them we know.
现在有足够的人知道了 就可以告诉他们我们知道
The lying and the secrets will be over.
谎言，秘密终于可以结束了
Or, we can not tell them we know and have a little fun of our own.
或者我们不要告诉他们我们知道 我们可以找点小乐子
We better go if we're gonna catch that movie.
好，该走了，如果想赶上电影的话
-Bye. -Bye.
-再见 -再见
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
再见，钱德，我已经开始想你了
Did you see the inappropriate pinching?
你看到了吗？ 她很不恰当地捏我一下？
Actually, I did.
我看到了
So now do you believe that she's attracted to me?
你现在相信她喜欢上我了吧？
Oh, my God! My God, she knows about us!
我的天！ 我的天，她知道我们的事！
-Phoebe knows about us! -I didn't tell them.
-菲比知道我们的事！ -我没有告诉她们
Them? Who's them?
她们？谁是她们？
Phoebe and Joey.
菲比和乔伊
Joey!
乔伊！
And Rachel.
还有瑞秋
They made me promise not to tell.
我本来要告诉你们的 可是她们要我答应不说
They think they are so slick, messing with us!
她们以为他们很厉害，玩我们！
They don't know that we know that they know.
可是，他们不知道 我们知道他们知道
-So... -Ah, yes!
-所以… -对！
The messers become the messees!
玩人的变成被玩的！
My God, he wants me to come over and feel his biceps!
我的天，他要我过去 摸他的二头肌还有别的！
Are you kidding?
你开玩笑？
I can't believe he'd do that to Mo..
我不相信他会对摩妮卡这样…
Joey? Do they know that we know?
乔伊？他们知道我们知道了吗？
-No. -Joey!
-不 -乔伊！
-They know you know. -I knew it!
-他们知道你们知道 -我就知道！
I cannot believe those two!
不能相信这两个人！
They thought that they could mess with us? With us?
他们以为可以玩我们？ 他们想要玩我们？
They don't know that we know they know we know.
他们不知道我们知道 他们知道我们知道
Joey, you can't say anything.
乔伊，你什么也不能说
Couldn't if I wanted to.
即使我想说也不知道要怎么说
She wants me to put lotion on her!
这完全失控了！ 她要我替她抹乳液！
She's bluffing!
她说大话！
She's not backing down. She went like this.
她没有退缩，她像这样：
He's not backing down. He went to get lotion.
他没有退缩，他去拿乳液了
Aren't you guys done yet?
你们还没玩完吗？
The sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler the sooner this is all over.
菲比早点攻破钱德 这事就早一点完全公开
-I like that. -Okay.
-我喜欢 -好
Okay, show him your bra. He's afraid of bras. Can't work them.
好，给他看你的内衣 他最怕内衣，他不会解内衣
Wow! You didn't rip off any buttons.
哇！你没拉掉任何扣子
It's not my first time.
这不是第一次
You go seduce her until she cracks.
回去那儿 勾引她直到解决她
Okay, give me a second.
好，给我一秒钟
-Did you clean up in here? -Of course.
-你清理了这儿？ -当然
Oh, you're going?
你要走了？
Not without you, lover.
除非你一起来，爱人
So, this is my bra.
这是我的内衣
It's very, very nice.
非常非常的好看
Well, come here.
过来
I'm happy we're gonna have all the sex.
我非常开心我们要上床了
You should be. I'm very bendy.
你应该开心的，我的柔软度很好
-I'm gonna kiss you. -Not if I kiss you first.
-我现在要吻你了 -如果我没先吻你的话
There's nothing left for us to do but kiss.
我想我们除了接吻 没有别的事可做了
Here it comes.
来了
Our first kiss.
我们的初吻
-Okay, okay, okay, fine, you win! -Ha!
-好，好，好，好，你赢了！ -哈！
-I can't have sex. -Why not?
-我不能和你上床 -为什么不？
-I'm in love with Monica. -You're what?
-因为我爱摩妮卡 -你什么？
Love her! That's right, I love her! I love her!
爱她！对，我爱她！ 我爱她！
I love you, Monica.
我爱你，摩妮卡
I love you too, Chandler.
我也爱你，钱德
I thought you guys were doing it, I didn't know you were in love.
我以为你们两个只是上床 我不知道你们恋爱了
That's it, it's over. Everybody knows.
就是这样，结束了 大家都知道了
-Well, Ross doesn't. -We'd like it if no one told him yet.
-其实，罗斯还不知道 -请大家先不要告诉他
No.
不
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Get off my sister!
放开我妹妹！
Friends getting married, it's gotta change things.
朋友要结婚了 很多事会改变的
Think it'll be different?
你想会不一样吗？
How can it not be? They're gonna have kids...
怎么能不变呢？ 他们很快会有小孩…
and hang out with other couples who have kids.
会和其他有孩子的夫妇在一起
And maybe they'll leave the city...
也许他们会搬离城市…
to be near a Volvo dealership.
到某个靠近富豪车商的地方
Things change.
事情会变的
I don't want them to move to a Volvo dealership.
我不要他们搬到 卖富豪车的地方
It'll be okay, Joe.
乔伊，会没事的
Sorry. I just.. I like things the way they are.
抱歉，我只是… 我希望能像以前一样
Who's this little naked guy?
这个光着身子的小孩是谁？
That naked guy would be me.
这个光着身子的小孩是我
Look at the little thing.
你看看这小东西
Yes.
是啊
Yes, fine, that is my penis. Can we be grownups now?
是，好，那是我的小鸡鸡 我们现在可以做大人了吗？
-Who are those people? -Got me.
-这些是谁？ -问倒我了
Oh, that's Nana right there.
那中间的是奶奶
-Wow. -Let's see.
-哇 -我看看
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
“我和在爪哇乔店里的那一群”
Monica, you look like your grandma. How old was she?
摩妮卡，你很像你祖母 那时她几岁？
Let's see,1939.
我看看，1939
Yeah,24,25.
对，24，25
Looks like a fun gang.
看来很快乐的一群
Look, look, look! I got Monica naked.
看，看，看！ 我找到摩妮卡光着身子的
Let me see.
我看
No, that would be me again.
不，这还是我
-Hey, you guys. -What's going on?
-嘿，大伙儿 -怎么样啊？
Well, we were just talking about...
我们刚刚提到…
you guys getting married and how great it is.
你们要结婚了，非常的好
Yeah, you can get a Volvo. If that's what you really want.
对，你们会买一台富豪 如果你们真的要那样
That's so sweet.
你们真好
-So, we both finished our vows. -Can we read them?
-我们都写完了婚誓 -可以看吗？
As long as I don't hear his and he doesn't hear mine.
只要我不看到钱德的 他不看到我的就好
Oh, that's beautiful.
好美
Funny one! Good!
好好笑！很好！
Will you marry me?
摩妮卡，你嫁给我好吗？
What? I don't get it.
什么？我不懂
Oh, yeah!
是呦！
-Man, this is hilarious! -Chandler!
-这太爆笑了！ -钱德！
Don't worry, we'll make yours funnier.
甜心，别担心 我们会让你的好笑一点
Okay, what do you think?
你们觉得如何？
-Dude... -I have never known love like this.
-老兄… -我从没见过这样的爱
-You really like it? -Dude!
-你真的喜欢？ -老兄！
How did you write this?
你怎么写出来的？
I stole Monica's and changed the name.
我偷了摩妮卡的 改成我的名字
-You can't do that! -If he goes first he can!
-你不能这么做！ -如果他先讲的话就可以！